A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1948
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1948
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.552
This collection consists of 6,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 17 December 1955.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1948 (Box 1)
  - Airport (Milton) 1948 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Office 1948 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education - General 1948 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education - printed & mimeographed material 1948 (Box 1)
  - Ancient Languages 1948 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1948 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions 1948 (Box 1)
  - Army ROTC - Transportation Corps 1948 (Box 1)
  - Army - General 1948 (Box 1)
  - Art & Architecture 1948 (Box 1)
  - Art Commission 1948 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Universities 1948 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Universities - Memorandum 1948 (Box 1)
  - Astronomy 1948 (Box 2)
  - Athletics 1948 (Box 2)
  - Athletics - Commonwealth Day 1948 (Box 2)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association 1948 (Box 2)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1948 (Box 2)
  - "Ba - Be" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 2)
  - "Bg - Bz" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 2)
  - Biology 1948 (Box 2)
  - Biology - Blandy Farm 1948 (Box 2)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Chemistry 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Commons 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Dry Dock 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Electricity 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Emergency Housing: General 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Emergency Housing: Copeley Hill 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Emergency Housing: Costs 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Emergency Housing: Temporary Academic Building 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Emergency Housing: Faculty Housing 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Federal Public Housing Authority 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Speech Building 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Temporary Buildings: Engineering 1948 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Fraternity Houses 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Fuel 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Geology Department 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Hospital 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Law Department 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Library 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Richey Property 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Roads 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Rotunda 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Scott Stadium 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Sewage Disposal 1948 (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Telephone System 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - General 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Architects and Engineers 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Cabell Hall 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Chemistry 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Contracts 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Engineering 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Faculty Apartments 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Field Artillery Reserves Building 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Fruit Research Laboratory 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Geological Survey Building 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Law Department 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Marine Corps Reserve Building 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Medical Buildings 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Men's Dormitories 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Naval Armory 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Physics 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Power Plant and Heating Mains 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Site Plans 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - University Press 1948 (Box 3)
  - Building Program - Women's Dormitory 1948 (Box 3)
  - Bursar's Office 1948 (Box 3)
  - Byrd, Senator H. F. 1948 (Box 3)
  - "Ca - Cl" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 4)
  - "Cm - Cz" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 4)
  - Caps and Gowns 1948 (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1948 (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Corporation for the Advancement of Teaching 1948 (Box 4)
  - Catalogue 1948 (Box 4)
  - Chemistry 1948 (Box 4)
  - College Topics (see Cavalier Daily) 1948 (Box 4)
  - Commerce and Economics 1948 (Box 4)
  - Committee - Administrative 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Bookstore 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Cabell Hall 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Calendar 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Chaperones' 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - to confer on Disposition of Million Dollars Appropriated by Legislature for Academic Building 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Liberal Arts 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Local Building 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Medical School Building 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Post-War College 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Publications 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Radio 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Research 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Schedule and Classroom Assignments 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Service Fellowships and Scholarships 1948 (Box 5)
  - Committee - Tree 1948 (Box 5)
  - Commons 1948 (Box 5)
  - Convocation 1948 (Box 5)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 5)
  - Dean Finley 1948 (Box 5)
  - Dean Ferguson 1948 (Box 5)
  - Dean Hollingsworth 1948 (Box 5)
  - Dean Lewis 1948 (Box 5)
  - Dean Newman's Office 1948 (Box 5)
  - Assistant Dean's Office 1948 (Box 5)
  - Development Fund 1948 (Box 5)
  - Development Fund 1948 (Box 6)
  - Dry Dock 1948 (Box 6)
  - DuPont Trust 1948 (Box 6)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 6)
  - Education - General 1948 (Box 6)
  - Education - English 1948 (Box 6)
  - Education - Graduate 1948 (Box 6)
  - Education - Nursing 1948 (Box 6)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board General Correspondence 1948 (Box 6)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board: Investments 1948 (Box 6)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board: Meetings 1948 (Box 6)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board: Treasurer 1948 (Box 6)
  - Endowment - Alumni Board: Contingent Fund 1948 (Box 6)
  - Engineering Department 1948 (Box 6)
  - Extension Division 1948 (Box 6)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 7)
  - Faculty 1948 (Box 7)
  - Foreign Affairs, School of 1948 (Box 7)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - General 1948 (Box 7)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly-Tiffany 1948 (Box 7)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1948 (Box 7)
  - Finals 1948 (Box 7)
  - Seward Forest 1948 (Box 7)
  - Forestry 1948 (Box 7)
  - Forms and Form Letters 1948 (Box 7)
  - Founder's Day 1948 (Box 7)
  - Fraternities 1948 (Box 7)
  - Friends of the University 1948 (Box 7)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 7)
  - Garden Club 1948 (Box 7)
  - General Education Board 1948 (Box 8)
  - Geography 1948 (Box 8)
  - Geology 1948 (Box 8)
  - Geological Survey 1948 (Box 8)
  - Germanic Languages 1948 (Box 8)
  - Gifts to the University 1948 (Box 8)
  - Governor's Office 1948 (Box 8)
  - Graduate Department 1948 (Box 9)
  - "Ha - He" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 9)
  - "Hf - Hz" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 9)
  - History 1948 (Box 9)
  - History Commission - World War II 1948 (Box 9)
  - Honor System 1948 (Box 9)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 9)
  - Institute of International Education 1948 (Box 9)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1948 (Box 9)
  - Insurance 1948 (Box 9)
  - Legislative Program: 1946-1948 1948 (Box 10)
  - Library 1948 (Box 10)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1948 (Box 10)
  - Library - McGregor Library 1948 (Box 10)
  - Library - Taylor Room 1948 (Box 10)
  - Madison Hall 1948 (Box 10)
  - Marine Corps 1948 (Box 10)
  - McIntire Fund 1948 (Box 10)
  - Mathematics 1948 (Box 10)
  - "M" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 10)
  - Mary Washington College 1948 (Box 10)
  - Medical Department 1948 (Box 10)
  - Medical Department - Hospital 1948 (Box 11)
  - Medical Department - Ward Patient Reports 1948 (Box 11)
  - Medical Department - Nursing School 1948 (Box 11)
  - Medical Department - Student Health 1948 (Box 11)
  - Military - Miscellaneous (see also Army, Navy, Marine Corps, etc.) 1948 (Box 11)
  - Samuel Miller Fund 1948 (Box 11)
  - Music 1948 (Box 11)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 11)
  - National Association of State Universities 1948 (Box 11)
  - National Education Association 1948 (Box 11)
  - Naval ROTC 1948 (Box 11)
  - Navy 1948 (Box 11)
  - Newcomb, Dr. J. L. 1948 (Box 11)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 11)
  - Oak Ridge 1948 (Box 11)
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 11)
  - Personnel 1948 (Box 11)
  - Personnel and Placement Office 1948 (Box 11)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1948 (Box 11)
  - Philosophy 1948 (Box 11)
  - Physical Education 1948 (Box 12)
  - Physics 1948 (Box 12)
  - Political Science 1948 (Box 12)
  - Psychology 1948 (Box 12)
  - Printing 1948 (Box 12)
  - Publications and Clippings 1948 (Box 12)
  - Bureau of Public Administration 1948 (Box 12)
  - Purchase and Printing (State Office) 1948 (Box 12)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 12)
  - Questionnaires 1948 (Box 12)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 12)
  - Radio WUVA 1948 (Box 12)
  - Recommendation, Letters of 1948 (Box 12)
  - Regional Education 1948 (Box 12)
  - Registration 1948 (Box 12)
  - Religion 1948 (Box 12)
  - Requisitions 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - General 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - Army Research 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - League of Virginia Counties 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - Geographical Institute 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - Medical Research 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - Ordnance Research Laboratory 1948 (Box 12)
  - Research - Public Health Service 1948 (Box 12)
  - Richmond University Center 1948 (Box 13)
  - Romance Languages 1948 (Box 13)
  - Rural Social Economics 1948 (Box 13)
  - "S" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 13)
  - Segregation 1948 (Box 13)
  - Selection Service 1948 (Box 13)
  - Sigma Xi 1948 (Box 13)
  - Sociology 1948 (Box 13)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1948 (Box 13)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1948 (Box 13)
  - Southern University Conference 1948 (Box 13)
  - Speech and Drama 1948 (Box 13)
  - State Board of Education 1948 (Box 13)
  - Statistics 1948 (Box 13)
  - Student Affairs 1948 (Box 13)
  - Sullivan Award 1948 (Box 14)
  - Summer Session 1948 (Box 14)
  - Surplus Property 1948 (Box 14)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 14)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 14)
  - United States Office of Education 1948 (Box 14)
  - University News Service 1948 (Box 14)
  - University Press 1948 (Box 14)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 14)
  - Veterans 1948 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1948 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Education Association 1948 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Music Festival 1948 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1948 (Box 14)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1948 (Box 14)
  - Visitors - Correspondence 1948 (Box 14)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes 1948 (Box 14)
  - Visitors - Mr. Anderson 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Judge Barksdale 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. Black 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Calcott 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. Carrington 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. Garnett 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gay 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gravatt 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. Mears 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mr. G. Tyler Miller 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Dr. Trout 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Wailes 1948 (Box 16)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Willis 1948 (Box 16)
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 16)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1948 (Box 16)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1948 (Box 16)